[
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 22,
        "y_pos1": 19,
        "move": 128,
        "id": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Sentri",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A stately baron",
            "job": "I rule this province.",
            "heal": "Very well.",
            "keyword1": "PROV",
            "keyword2": "WORD",
            "answer1": "Yes, these islands and much more.",
            "answer2": "I know but one of three syllables-'cor'.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou know the four cities of courage?",
            "yesanswer": "Very good.",
            "noanswer": "They are Jhelom, Minoc, Trinsic and Skara Brae."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 1,
        "tile1": 31,
        "x_pos1": 15,
        "y_pos1": 7,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "the gate guard.",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A very big guard.",
            "job": "Guard the gates, of course.",
            "heal": "Very strong!",
            "keyword1": "GATE",
            "keyword2": "GUAR",
            "answer1": "These are the gates to Serpent castle.",
            "answer2": "Guard, watch, protect.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou here to find courage?",
            "yesanswer": "Then thou art at the right place.",
            "noanswer": "Then perhaps to become a guard!"
        }
    },
    {
        ,
    "id"
    :
    2,
    "flag"
    :
    5,
    "humility"
    :
    0,
    "turningaway"
    :
    0,
    "talks"
    :
    {
        "name": "Lassorn",
        "pronoun": "He",
        "look": "A wounded sailor",
        "job": "I am a sailor.",
        "heal": "I alone survived the shipwreck.",
        "keyword1": "SHIP",
        "keyword2": "WHEE",
        "answer1": "The H.M.S. Cape.",
        "answer2": "She went down in the deep waters of the bay in the Cape of Heroes!",
        "yesnoquestion": "Ever heard of her?",
        "yesanswer": "She was a mighty vessel!",
        "noanswer": "She was a mighty vessel!"
    }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 3,
        "tile1": 56,
        "x_pos1": 26,
        "y_pos1": 12,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 3,
        "flag": 4,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Roark",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A seasoned fighter.",
            "job": "I fight for Britannia!",
            "heal": "Just healed.",
            "keyword1": "ABYS",
            "keyword2": "CODE",
            "answer1": "The Great Stygian Abyss holds the codex of ultimate wisdom!",
            "answer2": "I know little.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou well?",
            "yesanswer": "Then strive to find the secrets of the abyss.",
            "noanswer": "Thou hast come to the right place."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 4,
        "tile1": 37,
        "x_pos1": 24,
        "y_pos1": 17,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 4,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a ranger.",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A ranger engrossed in training.",
            "job": "I am training!",
            "heal": "Excellent.",
            "keyword1": "TRAI",
            "keyword2": "DUNG",
            "answer1": "I train so that I might survive the dungeons!",
            "answer2": "I plan to conquer the secret of the altar rooms.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou?",
            "yesanswer": "Ask our teacher about the rooms for she knowns much!",
            "noanswer": "Wimp."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 5,
        "tile1": 44,
        "x_pos1": 6,
        "y_pos1": 16,
        "move": 1,
        "id": 5,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Shyra",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "The training master.",
            "job": "I train warriors to fight with courage!",
            "heal": "Prime.",
            "keyword1": "TRAI",
            "keyword2": "ROOM",
            "answer1": "Train well and thy courage can grow with confidence.",
            "answer2": "In the altar room of courage use the red, orange, purple and white stones!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Wilt thou train?",
            "yesanswer": "Bravo!",
            "noanswer": "Pity."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 6,
        "tile1": 36,
        "x_pos1": 12,
        "y_pos1": 12,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 6,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a baronial guard",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A stern guard.",
            "job": "I guard our lord",
            "heal": "Most good.",
            "keyword1": "LORD",
            "keyword2": "CAST",
            "answer1": "Sentri rules this castle.",
            "answer2": "This castle is built on courage.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou wish an audience with Sentri?",
            "yesanswer": "Granted, enter.",
            "noanswer": "Then do not disturb him."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 7,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 13,
        "y_pos1": 9,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 7,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a treasure guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A burly guard",
            "job": "We guard our lord's treasure.",
            "heal": "Excellent.",
            "keyword1": "TREA",
            "keyword2": "DUNG",
            "answer1": "This treasure is not for thee",
            "answer2": "Seek out Durham for knowledge of dungeons.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou intend to steal our lord's treasure?",
            "yesanswer": "Fool!",
            "noanswer": "Wise move!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 8,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 23,
        "y_pos1": 9,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 8,
        "flag": 3,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Garam",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A bold fighter.",
            "job": "I fight with courage!",
            "heal": "Quite well.",
            "keyword1": "COUR",
            "keyword2": "BELL",
            "answer1": "Courage makes kings out of knaves!",
            "answer2": "The bell of courage lies at the bottom of a deep well at sea found at lat-N'A"
            long-L
            'A"",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou?",
            "yesanswer": "Good.",
            "noanswer": "Then train!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 9,
        "tile1": 37,
        "x_pos1": 8,
        "y_pos1": 26,
        "move": 1,
        "id": 9,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Durham",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A tall fighter.",
            "job": "I quest for glory!",
            "heal": "Fairly well.",
            "keyword1": "QUES",
            "keyword2": "DUNG",
            "answer1": "I feel that when on a quest my life has purpose!",
            "answer2": "The altar room of courage gives the third part of a key.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou on a quest?",
            "yesanswer": "Then thy life has meaning!",
            "noanswer": "What a loss."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 10,
        "tile1": 37,
        "x_pos1": 22,
        "y_pos1": 26,
        "move": 1,
        "id": 10,
        "flag": 3,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Lori",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A buxom guard.",
            "job": "I guard this passage.",
            "heal": "So far, so good.",
            "keyword1": "GARA",
            "keyword2": "DURH",
            "answer1": "He is in the west chamber.",
            "answer2": "He is in the east chamber.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou looking for someone?",
            "yesanswer": "Who?",
            "noanswer": "Then be on thy way!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 11,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 27,
        "y_pos1": 26,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 11,
        "flag": 3,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Samuel",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A handsome guard",
            "job": "I guard this passage.",
            "heal": "So far, so good.",
            "keyword1": "GARA",
            "keyword2": "DURH",
            "answer1": "He is in the west chamber.",
            "answer2": "He is in the east chamber.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou looking for someone?",
            "yesanswer": "Who?",
            "noanswer": "Then be on thy way!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 12,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 3,
        "y_pos1": 26,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 12,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Roderick",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A destitute, stinking beggar.",
            "job": "I cannot work.",
            "heal": "I've lost a hand!",
            "keyword1": "HAND",
            "keyword2": "ORBS",
            "answer1": "It was eaten by a zorn.",
            "answer2": "An orb of blue light will raise thy strength, dexterity or intelligence, but at a cost!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Wilt thou give me gold?",
            "yesanswer": "Thou art kind.",
            "noanswer": "Stingy!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 13,
        "tile1": 88,
        "x_pos1": 11,
        "y_pos1": 29,
        "move": 0,
        "id": 13,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Sister Antos",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A wise druid.",
            "job": "I have important information.",
            "heal": "Well enough.",
            "keyword1": "INFO",
            "keyword2": "BELL",
            "answer1": "On what subject?",
            "answer2": "The bell of courage is needed to enter the abyss.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou have it?",
            "yesanswer": "Very good.",
            "noanswer": "Then ask the fighter Garam for he knows where it lies!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 14,
        "tile1": 36,
        "x_pos1": 3,
        "y_pos1": 5,
        "move": 1,
        "id": 14,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Noxum",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A spiny nixie!",
            "job": "I swim the seas!",
            "heal": "Nice and wet!",
            "keyword1": "SEAS",
            "keyword2": "SHIP",
            "answer1": "There are many ships at the bottom!",
            "answer2": "A survivor would know where to search.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou heard of the H.M.S. Cape?",
            "yesanswer": "She had a magical wheel that would strengthen her hull!",
            "noanswer": "A great ship!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 15,
        "tile1": 133,
        "x_pos1": 15,
        "y_pos1": 2,
        "move": 1,
        "id": 15,
        "flag": 4,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Michelle",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A beautiful paladin!",
            "job": "I welcome thee unto Serpent Castle!",
            "heal": "Very well.",
            "keyword1": "SENT",
            "keyword2": "HEAL",
            "answer1": "He is the lord here, take the west passage.",
            "answer2": "Take the east passage.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou well?",
            "yesanswer": "Very good, perhaps thou seeks Sentri.",
            "noanswer": "Then thou should visit our healer!"
        }
    }
]